Do you know which kind of comments always trigger me and always prompt me to correct people?
My answer is always it's not latex because most of the time when people comment this it's PVC
But there is a huge difference between these two materials and today
I'm going to tell you that even though they look alike they're not comparable at all
Alright, I changed outfit and you can take a guess now. Is it latex or is it PVC?
It's PVC! And for answering your questions regarding the difference I have held today,
I asked Honor from London, a really established clothing brand that has not only PVC and latex
items but also all kind of different styles. And I have now Isabella here as a guest and I'm going
to ask you the first question right away. Isabella, what's the difference between latex and PVC?
Hi Celine, thank you for inviting me on today. So latex and PVC are very popular items but the two
have distinct characteristics. PVC is plastic coated known for its durability. PVC is easier
to get into than latex and less figure-hugging. Latex on the other hand, like my dress, is a
natural rubber and fits much tighter to the skin. It has a very specific smell and feel which people
like myself adore. Great, thank you. What are the differences regarding care of latex and PVC?
Maintaining these materials is important for making your products last longer. Both materials
are hand wash only. PVC is fairly low maintenance requiring simple cleaning with mild soap and water.
You'll want to hand wash latex with a small amount of soap or spray and it's important to keep it
away from sunlight, excessive heat and oil-based products. Regular polishing with silicon-based
serums like this one will help preserve your latex. This will give your latex a glorious shine.
You can also use this as a dresser to help you get into your latex. All right so if people come
into the online store what would you tell them who should buy which material? Tough question.
So latex is an iconic style which fits and feels and looks a certain way which people love and
adore. PVC like I'm wearing now is much easier to get in and out of and it has a beautiful shine
naturally. So ultimately it comes down to personal preference. Consider your priorities. Is it low
maintenance or elasticity? Both materials have their benefits and choosing one which aligns with
your needs is best. But now the personal question, what is your favourite material and why? I honestly
love both. I usually wear latex when I want my outfit skin tight and figure hugging, whereas I
I wear PVC when I wish for something a bit more breathable.
Depends on my mood that day.
I hope this guide helps you navigate
the latex and PVC dilemma.
Thank you.
Thank you Isabella for answering these questions
and I of course am wearing a honor outfit at the moment.
It's a PVC outfit from the Rings Collection
and it is really special because it is four way stretch
and really glossy so that is kind of my favorite
kind of PVC.
I changed into a latex dress also from Honor clothing and it's one of my
favorite latex items from them because it just looks so good. I put the links in
the description text of course and also I have a discount code you can use it to
get 20% off it's Ixtellin20 but as I said just check out the description text.
I think the best way to show you this difference is to show them side by side.
side. Yeah so both dresses look pretty similar but let me point out some
indicators how you can tell the difference between the latex and PVC. PVC
is most of the time a bit more loose fitting so you'll have more ruffles or
wrinkles here in the material and it's not like glued to the skin but like
normal fabric it can slide a bit more on the skin and therefore has a different
fit not as tight mostly. Next point is that with PVC you have stitchings
because it's sewn together whereas with latex you don't have stitchings or
visible seam lines so to say because it's glued together so always
Please watch out if you can tell if there are some machine-sewn lines here in which
you can see the yarn.
Maybe you hear it but PVC makes a lot of noise and there are some PVC fabrics that make even
more noise than this one whereas latex is a pretty quiet material because it doesn't
move as much but stays in place.
So in general if the outfit sits really tight and snug and looks like a second skin then
it's probably latex but if you can see a lot of wrinkles, a lot of stitching, a lot of
seam lines then normally it's PVC.
And also be aware a lot of the companies mislabel their products and say it's PVC or latex when
it's not but the opposite.
So my advice is shop at webshops or in shops where they can tell the difference because
they have to be the experts.
So head over to the Honor website and have a look there.
You can select if you want to see PVC, latex, wet look or leather and then you can start
shopping and buy some nice stuff.
Another tip I totally forgot, by the way I'm wearing latex again.
If you're not sure, just check out if there is a description text of the picture or the video
and if the person states that it's PVC or latex.
But just don't assume it's latex because it's shiny.
Thank you very much for your attention.
No really, it is a pet peeve of mine to like be it's not latex when it's not and often it's not.
Yeah, I don't know if you can relate to that but I thought this is a nice way to explain
it to you and to point out the differences.
So again, thanks to Honor for helping me out here and I hope you enjoyed this video.
Leave a comment and a thumbs up, check out the Honor webshop and I will see you in the
next video.
Have a good time.
Bye.
A little puzzle at the end.
I'm wearing both now, which you have noticed.
And is it okay to mix both of them up?